A Catalog of Instrumental Music Published Before ca. 1800 in the Alexander Mackay-Smith Collection of the University of Virginia
University of Virginia Library
- SEI TRIO A DUE VIOLINI E BASSO Dedicati all'Illustrissimo Signore DON GIUSEPPE FOWKE Composti da FRANCESCO ZAPPA Maestro di S.A.R. IL DUCA D'YORK OPERA SECONDA LONDON Printed by WELCKER in Gerrard Street St. Ann's Soho Where may be had Sonatas for 2 Violins and a Bass by the following Masters [lis
  Trio sonatas, op. 2; Zappa, Francesco, fl. 1763-1788; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; Welcker, Peter, d. 1775; London (England); Minuet; B♭; C; D; E♭; G; 2/4; 3/4; 3/8; Allegro con brio; Andante; Andantino; Largo; Minuetto; Minuetto grazioso; Presto
  - VIOLINO PRIMO
  - VIOLINO SECONDO
  - BASSO
- THE true METHOD of PLAYING an Adagio Made Easy by twelve Examples First. in a plain Manner with a Bass Then with all their Graces Adapted for those who Study the VIOLIN Composed by Carlo Zuccari OF MILAN LONDON. Printed by R: BREMNER, at the Harp and Hautboy, opposite Somerset House in the STRAND., 1762; Z354; Score, folio, 170x248 (189x264): Title, verso blank. Music, pp. 1-12.
  Adagio I D
  Adagio II B♭
  Adagio III C
  Adagio IV F
  Adagio V a
  Adagio VI g
  Adagio VII e
  Adagio VIII E♭
  Adagio IX A
  Adagio X d
  Adagio XI c
  Adagio XII G
  True method of playing an adagio; Zuccari, Carlo, 1704-1792; Harp and Hautboy; Bremner, Robert, d. 1789; London (England); A; B♭; C; D; E♭; F; G; E; 3/4; C|; [no indication]
  The music consists of three staves. From bottom to top, they are: (1) a figured bass; (2) an unembellished violin part; (3) an embellished violin part. The incipits for this entry are taken from (3).